Vivian Chen

vivianc206@gmail.com | 917.353.2308 | Github | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Data analyst with 3+ years of experience in creating and aggregating data, generating visualizations, and writing documentation. Strong interests in understanding urban infrastructure patterns, public transportation accessibility, and intuitive design. Seeking opportunities to apply and enhance data mining and programming skills to create solutions for real-life applications, urban issues, and company efficiency.

EDUCATION AND HONORS

NYU Center for Urban Science and Progress

Master of Science in Applied Urban Science and Informatics

- Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning for Cities, Big Data Management and Analytics, Democracy for Cities, Urban Spatial Analytics; Civic Analytics and Urban Intelligence; Applied Data Science; Principles of Urban Informatics; Data Governance Ethics and Privacy
- Member of the Applied Urban Science Group (AUSG)

Macaulay Honors College at Hunter College (CUNY)

New York, NY

Bachelor of Arts in Geographical Information Science

Minors in Computer Science and Media Studies

08/2015 - 06/2019

Expected Graduation: 07/2020

Member of Gamma Theta Upsilon (GTU)

SKILLS

- Coding Languages and Database Applications: Python, SQL, VBA, Microsoft Access
- GIS Software: ArcGIS, QGIS
- **Design:** HTML, CSS, Adobe (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign)
- Languages: English (native), Mandarin (conversational), Cantonese (conversational), French (basic)

WORK EXPERIENCE

New York City Economic Development Corporation

01/2020 - Present

Transportation Intern

Working in the Planning Division to research NYCEDC waterfront, transit, and housing projects

New York City Department of Transportation

GIS College Aide

03/2018 - 02/2020

- Worked within the Asset Management Unit to create and maintain geodatabases through customized scripts using Python, SQL, and VBA
- Used ArcMap, ArcCatalog, and QGIS to create and edit maps and metadata of NYC DOT assets
- Created dashboards using MS Excel and MS Access for data visualization and projection analysis
- Through MS Access, designed a database to track seating arrangements for all DOT floors within the 55 Water St. building to streamline the agency's emergency preparedness procedures

Barnard College, Empirical Reasoning Center

08/2019 - 12/2019

Teaching Assistant

- Supported Prof. Alisa Rod in the lab section of the GIS Methods course through guiding students on using GIS
- Graded weekly labs and hold office hours for students

The Graduate Center, City University of New York

Research Intern

08/2017 - 01/2019

• Conducted research to create a database of NYC architecture and generated an interactive map via CARTO for Dr. Elizabeth Macaulay-Lewis' publication: Classical New York Discovering Greece and Rome in Gotham

American Geographical Society

Scholar Intern

09/2016 - 12/2016

- Maintained and updated AGS blogging sites, UBIQUE and Connect2Conserve, and interviewed companies and non-profit organizations for weekly Spotlight articles
- Prepared for the annual Fall Symposium, *Geography 2050* by creating graphics for promotional items, advertising on social media, and working on-site to ensure a smooth run-of-the-show